# 大家好 現在又快過了一年啦
Hi everyone! Now a year has almost passed.
# 我去看一下兄弟家後山的那個魚塘啊
I'm going to have a look at the pond on my buddy's hill.
# 看他的魚有沒有大 帶了點網
Let's see if the fish have grown up. I have some nets with me.
# 過去
Let's go!
# 就在前面
It's right over there.
# 這個山泉水好舒服啊
The spring water is really great!
# 喝一口
Have a sip.
# 好多很小的魚 肯定是上面跑下來的
There're a lot of small fish. They must be coming down from up there.
# 你看 終於到啦 就在上面
Look! We're here finally. It's right up there.
# 現在我們抄個近路
We're now taking a shortcut.
# 把這個網拆一下
Let me untie the net.
# 就搞了根繩子
With a piece of string,
# 這樣就很方便
it's so much easier.
# 不用提
I don't need to hold it.
# 弄得亂七八糟的
What a mess!
# 哎喲 差一點摔一跤
Ayo! I almost fell.
# 還有一副網 要到上面去放
We have one more net. I'll put it up there.
# 這裡太危險
It's too dangerous here.
# 你看 這一副網
Look! Here's a net,
# 新網
new net.
# 這個漁網放好啦 我們明天再過來看一下
So the nets have been set. Let's come again tomorrow.
# 我們從這邊回去
We'll leave from this side.
# 第二天
Next day
# 今天我們來收網哦 網就在下面
We're coming to get back the nets today. The nets are just down there.
# 這還有點危險哦 這裡
It's still a bit dangerous here.
# 你看這個網 就在這下面這個
Look at the net! I mean the one just down there.
# 網都爛了
The net is torn.
# 哇 有
Wa! Yeah!
# 看到一條啦
I can see a fish.
# 那邊還有一副 我們去那邊
There's another net. Let's go to that side.
# 這還 這還有一副網
Here's one, here's one more net.
# 哇 哈哈
Wa! Ha ha!
# 有
Yeah!
# 哇塞
My god!
# 好多魚呀
So many fish!
# 差點走了
It almost escaped.
# 哇 這條大魚
Wa! It's a big fish!
# 哇 夠大了 這條
Wa! This is, big enough.
# 你看 這裡都差不多兩斤
Look! It's almost a kilogram here.
# 那麼大的 這個都已經有二兩
Big fish. This one alone is already a hundred grams.
# 把它綁起來 綁起來方便一點這個
Tie it up. It's easier to carry when it's tied up.
# 夠啦 回去啦
We have enough. Let's go back.
# 這個綏都報廢了 這個網
The net is written off, the net...
# 沒有 一次我們再買一個新的來
Never mind. We'll buy a new one next time.
# 把它的內臟去一下
I'm removing the guts.
# 這個內臟不好吃的
The guts are not tasty at all.
# 這個肉還很結實的哦
It's still very firm.
# 誒呦還想 夾我
Eya! It wants to, pinch me.
# 還想跑啊你
You think you can escape?
# 沒那麼容易
Impossible!
# 把它裡面那個肺給清掉
The lungs inside the crab need to be removed,
# 肺清掉了就可以吃的了
before the crab can be eaten.
# 誒呦 差點夾到我
Ayo! It almost pinched me.
# 好 全都清乾淨啦 清洗一下
Alright! All the guts are removed. Let's wash it.
# 清洗乾淨啦 我們放點油鹽醬油腌一下它
It's clean now. We'll marinate it with some sauce or salt or whatever.
# 洗把這個倒一下
Pour them all into the pot first.
# 小狗一直在叫
The puppies are screaming nonstop.
# 我先把小狗放下來
Let me get the puppies down first.
# 出來 出來出來出來
Come! Come come come!
# 它們就像土匪一樣 跟你說
They're just like bandits, you know.
# 切點生薑下去
Smash some ginger
# 加點鹽 這個鹽稍微加多一點
Put some salt. It needs more salt.
# 多放點鹽 咸一點才好吃
More salt. It tastes better only with more salt.
# 醬油
Soy sauce
# 料酒
Cooking wine
# 不醉不歸 多喝點啊
Juice them up! Drink more!
# 再加點我們這個蕉芋粉
And finally, our Indian shot powder.
# 這個稍微放多一點
We need a bit more of it.
# 好啦 再腌個半個小時 我們就開始
Alright! Marinate it for half and hour. Then we can start,
# 煎它啦
frying them,
# 用油來煎它
frying them with oil.
# 我現在把那個最肥的小豬把它放出來
I'm now going to get the fattest piggy, get it out.
# 那上好多那些剩飯剩菜啊
There's so much table scraps on the ground.
# 都沒人 沒人吃
Nobody wants it.
# 叫它下來吃
Let the piggy clear it.
# 你看這隻豬 我一來它都盯著我
Look at this pig! It stares at me once I get close.
# 那條最胖的小豬在那裡
The fattest piggy is over there.
# 把它搞出來
Let me get it out.
# 你看 這豬都過來圍著我了
Look! The pigs are all coming around me.
# 跟我有感情是不是
You like me, don't you?
# 過年要吃你們的肉哦
But your pork will be my new year dish, you know?
# 小豬 我來抓你出去誒
Piggy! I'm coming to get you out.
# 吃外面好吃噠 去不去吃
There's really good food out there. Don't you want it?
# 二四六八十 沒少吧
Two, four, six, eight, ten. All are here.
# 你那樣看著我幹嘛
Why are you staring at me with this sight?
# 想拱我是不是
You wanna attack me, don't you?
# 這公豬
This boar...!
# 拱人啊
It attacks me!
# 拿鞭子來
Let me get a whip.
# 竟然打我
It attacks me!
# 竟然想咬我
You wanna bite me!
# 別咬我啊 走開
Don't try to bite me! Go away!
# 借你的小孩玩一下 又不會幹嘛
I just wanna borrow your child. I'm not even doing any harm to it.
# 我又不會把你殺了
I won't kill you.
# 別過來
Don't come to me!
# 小豬 走 帶你去吃香的喝辣的
Piggy, let's go! I have tasty food and savory drinks for you.
# 看到我都怕 跑啦
It's so scared of me. It's running away.
# 你看 這條公的又不聽話
Look! The boar is so naughty!
# 想來拱我
It wants to attack me.
# 就是那條 最胖的那條
It's that one, the fattest one.
# 你看 全部都圍著我
Look! They're are coming around me.
# 不要跟它們玩
Leave them alone.
# 你們不要來
Don't come with me!
# 嘿 你來幹嘛
Hey! What are you doing here?
# 上下面去
Get back down there!
# 不要來
Don't come with me!
# 這公豬又來了
The boar is coming again!
# 等等 我來 哈哈
Wait! Let me take care of it! Ha ha!
# 你看 這樣不行的 這公的
Look! It doesn't work. The boar,
# 它要拱我 看到我抓它的小孩子
it wants to attack me. When it sees me catching its child,
# 就要來拱我
it comes to attack me.
# 搞不得搞不得
No, no, no!
# 下次來 下次來放
Next time! Get it next time!
# 走了
Let's go!
# 你看 這在公豬
Look! Now the boar,
# 它現在都很猛了
It's very fierce now.
# 翅膀都硬了
It's so arrogant.
# 跟 敢跟我對打
Fight, it even dares to fight with me.
# 我去抓它小豬 它是竟然 咬想
I just wanted to catch the piggy. But then it wanted to bite me!
# 太壞了
Too naughty!
# 誒 算啦
Ay! Forget it!
# 下次啦
I'll come again,
# 下次來吃你的肉
come again for your pork.
# 放點油
Put some oil.
# 放油一定要多
It needs a lot of oil.
# 不多油的話就不好炸了
Otherwise it's not good for frying.
# 這油熱得太慢了
The oil is heating up too slowly.
# 先等一下
Let's wait for a while.
# 誒呦差點忘了 這裡還有個辣椒粉
Ayo! I've almost forgotten that I still have some chili powder here.
# 加點辣椒粉去 更入味
It will be more flavourful with the chili powder.
# 這魚有有辣椒粉才更好吃的哦 這個魚
The fish taste so much better with the chili powder, the fish.
# 拿筷子去拌一下
Stir with the chopsticks.
# 現在 油溫夠燙啦
Now, the oil is hot enough.
# 下鍋咯
Into the wok!
# 誒呦
Eyyo!
# 你看 這樣煎起來很漂亮的哦
Look! It's so pretty then it's being fried.
# 這個魚都抱在一起
The fish are clinging together.
# 把它們分開
Let me separate them,
# 要一條一條把它分開
separate them one by one.
# 把得好緊啊
It's very tight!
# 現在很漂亮了哦
It's very pretty now.
# 也熟啦
And it's cooked.
# 把它撈起來
Let me get them out.
# 哎喲 掉了一條大條的
Ayo! I dropped a large one.
# 去 那麼一[SIC]條 給你們吃
Chee! A big fish, it's for you!
# 把這些也放進去
And now the rest.
# 讓我老弟煎一下 我去出嘗一下 看好不好吃
My younger brother will continue with the cooking. Let me have a try outside, and see if it tastes good.
# 哇 全部跟著我來了
Wa! They're all following me.
# 這小黑口水都流出來了
Blacky is already drooling.
# 嗯
Um!
# 真的很不錯
It's really not bad.
# 這味道太好啦
It's simply marvelous!
# 來 給母狗吃
Come! It's for the mother!
# 哇 這個
Wa! This is...
# 太大的魚不好煎
It's not too for frying if it the fish is too big.
# 誒呦 你看 小黑
Ayo! Look! Black!
# 你看 這個 這個母狗 很厲害哦 現在
Look! The, the mother, is really skillful now.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 等一下用來下飯
This will be part of my lunch.
# 放了點辣椒 味道還可以
With some chili, it tastes not bad.